<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Placeholder &amp; Co.</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Placeholder &amp; Co.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:12:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Week 12: Girls' Last Tour (of BKK)</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Week 12: Girls' Last Tour (of BKK)" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="station-1-chinatown"&gt;Station 1: Chinatown~
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For our first stop, we went to Chinatown after our KMITL visit (see prev. post~). After a long bus ride from our lab which took almost an hour (note: avoid Bangkok traffic on Friday..), we entered Chinatown and headed to the Kuan Yim Shrine which is Mahayana Buddhist, to offer some prayers. I sort of only did one and gave up because I was too sleepy, though KM and Khush did properly do the whole three rites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9379.jpeg"
width="4032"
height="3024"
srcset="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9379_hu_8a96ea48644d2de5.jpeg 480w, https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9379_hu_243a2618ca144984.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="shrine aesthetic"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
&gt; &lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/incense-lit.gif"
width="800"
height="1422"
srcset="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/incense-lit_hu_e9cd559bb1b886c2.gif 480w, https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/incense-lit_hu_a0c9c3d61f24775.gif 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="burning incense~"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="56"
data-flex-basis="135px"
&gt; &lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9377.jpeg"
width="4032"
height="3024"
srcset="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9377_hu_631504df6a4f6a1c.jpeg 480w, https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9377_hu_62aff0aeda8b3058.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="instructions"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, we headed off for our well-deserved dinner; KM had a place in mind and took the scariest, most long-winded path known to man to reach it. We were joking that he would kidnap us by bringing down a weird alleyway, so when we actually started heading down one, I found myself lowkey concerned&amp;hellip; Anyway, we ended up at a Michelin Bib Gourmand-rated restaurant (surprisingly many in Thailand btw) called Kuay Teow Kua Kai Suan Mali, which served Kuey Teow but fried into a crispy almost pancake-like dish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9383.jpeg"
width="4032"
height="3024"
srcset="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9383_hu_52fdc9ca196015ee.jpeg 480w, https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9383_hu_3c22da589ecad48c.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="group photo taken by yours truly"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I had pretty high expectations of the food quality as I noticed that: a), place was down a dingy alleyway, b), the menu was super tiny, and c), I mean come on its rated by Michelin. Why a) and b) though you may asK? Well, if a restaurant can look run-down yet have loads of customers then the food definitely would make up for it, and if they only make one thing, they&amp;rsquo;d better be pretty damn good at at! And indeed, it was more than above my expectations; when we order the Kuey Teow the skin was delightfully crispy and onsen eggs were absolutely perfect. In a way the fried Kuey Teow skin almost tasted like prata for some reason. Prices were very reasonable too, at 50 THB for small or 60 THB for the large, which is around 2 dollars for them. I uh, had two bowls&amp;hellip; and would&amp;rsquo;ve gotten more if I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel kinda unwell&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9391.jpeg"
width="4032"
height="3024"
srcset="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9391_hu_dc43c5218168f5a8.jpeg 480w, https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9391_hu_6df828f5d66777c6.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="china town gate"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
&gt; &lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9387.jpeg"
width="4032"
height="3024"
srcset="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9387_hu_633debd0fa46e642.jpeg 480w, https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9387_hu_9aeea50d11850e6d.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="cool pic 1"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
&gt; &lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9388.jpeg"
width="4032"
height="3024"
srcset="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9388_hu_a96bf9873829e765.jpeg 480w, https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/girls-last-tour/IMG_9388_hu_19bf60705a2740f8.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="cool pic 2"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wrapped up with Khush heading back himself as he lived in the area, whilst the rest of us took a bus back to our dorms to get a good night&amp;rsquo;s rest and prepare for our final day of our internship, and our second last day in thailand~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="station-2-pratunam-market"&gt;Station 2: Pratunam Market
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id="station-3-this-train-service-ends-at--suvarnabhumi-airport"&gt;Station 3: This Train Service ends at &amp;ndash; Suvarnabhumi Airport
&lt;/h2&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 12: Exploring KMITL</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/kmitl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/kmitl/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-kmitl-cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 12: Exploring KMITL" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="hua-lamphong-railway-station"&gt;Hua Lamphong Railway Station
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My manager, an undergrad, Andreaa, and I set off for King Mongkut&amp;rsquo;s Institute of Technology Ladkrabang (KMITL) to meet Professor Kitsuchart Pasupa and get a behind-the-scenes look at the SIT campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all gathered at Hua Lamphong Railway Station, thanks to my manager’s idea to hop on an old-school train for the full experience. The station itself was massive—seriously, it felt like stepping into a time machine with all the retro vibes.
&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-station.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Main view"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Hua Lamphong Railway Station&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After strolling through the main entrance, we spotted two trains on display. Not gonna lie, it totally gave off movie vibes—like Mr. Bean’s Holiday with all the chaos at Gare de Lyon in Paris, or those iconic Harry Potter moments at King’s Cross in London. It was a mashup of cinematic nostalgia! And get this—the train fare from Hua Lamphong to KMITL was just 6 Baht. Absolute bargain!
&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/railway-station.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Station view"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Huge!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/fir-train.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Train view"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Firdaus pointing the train&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/ticket.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Train view"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Ticket&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="train-view"&gt;Train view
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The train didn’t have any air conditioning, so we just let the breeze do its thing as we chugged along.
&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/old-train.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Old Train"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Front view of the train&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took about an hour to get from Hua Lamphong to KMITL, but the scenery along the way was honestly pretty awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-train-move2.gif"
loading="lazy"
alt="train moving"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;More Old Trains&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-plane.gif"
loading="lazy"
alt="Cinematic plane"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Cinematic Aeroplane View&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-train0move.gif"
loading="lazy"
alt="Old Train"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Town view&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kmitl"&gt;KMITL
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we finally arrived at KMITL, we grabbed some lunch before meeting the professors. At the SIT building, students were busy setting up booths for the Open House—which, sadly, was happening the next day, not today&amp;hellip;😭&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-open-house-setup.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Old Train"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;SIT Open House Preparation&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-openhouse-peace.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Old Train"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Peace Yo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once both professors showed up, our campus tour kicked off. The building was pretty unique—six floors, tight hallways, and rooms everywhere you looked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-tour1.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Old Train"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Start of our Tour!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the fourth floor, we stumbled into a game dev room sponsored by Metaverse. There were VR headsets everywhere and some gear that looked like it belonged in a sci-fi movie—think “VR space walk.” Super cool!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-game-dev.gif"
loading="lazy"
alt="Old Train"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;On the way to the game dev room...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-gaming-room.gif"
loading="lazy"
alt="Old Train"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Game Dev Room&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also checked out Professor Kitsuchart Pasupa’s lab to see one of the workstations they use for AI model testing. Fun fact: their “extra” air cooler was just a standing fan!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-fan-pc.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Old Train"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Cool fan&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the tour, two KMUTT students shared their strategies from the recent Cyber AI Cup 2025, where they represented Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-presentation.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Old Train"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Post presentation pic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They actually took home second place—huge congrats to them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-post-pic.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Old Train"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 12: Wrap Up</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/last-day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/last-day/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/week12-cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 12: Wrap Up" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="last-day-at-ic2-lab"&gt;Last day at IC2 Lab
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andreaa and I spent the day at the IC2 Lab finalizing deliverables, handing over documentation, and presenting our final updates to the manager. We reviewed outstanding tasks, ensured knowledge transfer, and confirmed next steps before signing off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-ic2.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Room view 1"
&gt; &lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-ic2-2.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Room view 2"
&gt; &lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-ic2-3.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Room view 3"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="our-managers-birthday"&gt;Our Manager&amp;rsquo;s Birthday
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After wrapping up and handing over our final materials, Andreaa and I joined the team to celebrate our manager’s birthday — a fitting end to the internship. Professor Jonathan stopped by and brought a cake for everyone; we shared stories, took photos, and thanked everyone for their support. It was a warm, uplifting send‑off that left us proud of what we accomplished and excited for what’s next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-bfday.gif"
loading="lazy"
alt="Enjoyable moments"
&gt; &lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-split.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Cake"
&gt; &lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week12-ic2-candid.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="IC2 members"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Neovim: A code editor for nerds</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/neovim-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:58:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/neovim-guide/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/neovim-guide/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Neovim: A code editor for nerds" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a developer, without a doubt you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of at least a few Integrated Development Environments (or IDEs for short), with the most common ones being Pycharm or Visual Studio Code (not to be confused with Visual Studio, thanks Microsoft for the totally not confusing naming schemes). But, unless you&amp;rsquo;re like a total nerd, what you probably haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of is: Neovim!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="so-whats-neovim--why-use-it"&gt;So, What&amp;rsquo;s Neovim &amp;amp; why use it?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neovim is a terminal-based text editor that focuses on efficient editing with the keyboard. The power in this may not be obvious, especially considering how universal the mouse is. Why would anyone want to use just their keyboard? Isn&amp;rsquo;t that just voluntarily handicapping yourself? Well, not so! In fact, the motions that you&amp;rsquo;re able to do with vim motions are incredibly powerful: allowing you to do nearly anything with just a few keystrokes. There&amp;rsquo;s the obvious things you&amp;rsquo;d expect with a text editor like moving around (but conveniently using just the home row), or inserting text, or selecting and deleting text. But, there&amp;rsquo;s so much more, like deleting whole words or whole lines, replacing text in brackets, and with certain plugins even replacing the contents of a function. I&amp;rsquo;ll cover the actual bindings in a later section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, for the code editing part: why in the world did I compare a text editor to IDEs? Well, Neovim is highly extensible and allows for the installation of plugins. This allows it to functionally become an IDE with enough configuration. The core way to do this is by fully building a configuration yourself from scratch in the configuration files, but for obvious reasons this is very daunting. Luckily though, there are many different things that help set Neovim up for you, from the simplest &lt;code&gt;kickstart.nvim&lt;/code&gt; which just gives you a base configuration file to start with, to LunarVim which gives you a fully-featured IDE from the get-go. Personally, I used LazyVim because that&amp;rsquo;s what my friend recommended me (and she&amp;rsquo;s a total nerd so I trust her). It lies in-between the bare minimum and a full setup, giving you some useful plugins and additional tools that you can install should you want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-2-neovim-not-really"&gt;How 2 Neovim (not really)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]
This isn&amp;rsquo;t really a guide but more of me just showcasing some of the things that you can do in Neovim, if you try to use this as a learning resource you might want to cry :3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll preface by saying that learning Vim keybindings is not intuitive whatsoever, and relies on you to put in the effort to do so. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say that they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;nonsensical&lt;/em&gt;, just that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come naturally. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend using the &lt;code&gt;:Tutor&lt;/code&gt; command in Neovim to learn the basics (or watch one of many helpful youtube videos). &lt;code&gt;:help&lt;/code&gt; is also a nice command, allowing you to get a reference for any command or binding using &lt;code&gt;:help [command you need help with]&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something important about (Neo)vim is that it is a modal text editor. This means that for example, there&amp;rsquo;s a mode for navigation and actions (Normal Mode), insertion of text (Insert Mode), and selection of text (Visual Mode). This is what trips people up the most in the beginning I feel, even more so than the weird keybindings. Learning to type &lt;code&gt;:q&lt;/code&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t the issue in quitting, often I find it&amp;rsquo;s accidentally entering insert mode, not even realising, and fruitlessly trying to quit from there. In conventional editors, there&amp;rsquo;s just one mode: editing. You use your mouse to navigate and select (usually), and your keyboard for inserting text, and that&amp;rsquo;s it. The major downside to this is constantly having to navigate back and forth the keyboard and mouse, which can feel tedious and can bring you out of the flow state&amp;hellip; Or maybe that&amp;rsquo;s just a nerd problem. But either way, things will get much smoother once you start learning how to enter the correct mode to do things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, for the important part, bindings! Now, who could neglect the beloved &lt;code&gt;hjkl&lt;/code&gt; to navigate? &lt;code&gt;h&lt;/code&gt; for left, &lt;code&gt;j&lt;/code&gt; for down, &lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; for up, and &lt;code&gt;l&lt;/code&gt; for right.their presence on the home row is so much nicer ergonomically speaking, compared to having to move my hands down in order to navigate. Other essential actions would be using &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt; to enter insert mode to actually edit your file, and &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt; to go back to normal mode once you&amp;rsquo;re done. Another important keybind is &lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt; in normal mode, which enters command mode and where if you&amp;rsquo;re sick of Neovim already you can then do &lt;code&gt;quit&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;q&lt;/code&gt; for short) to quit. (For ease of reading I&amp;rsquo;ll use &lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt; in front of command mode commands from here onwards. If you&amp;rsquo;ve made changes, you can use &lt;code&gt;:write&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;:w&lt;/code&gt; for short), or you can chain certain commands like &lt;code&gt;:wq&lt;/code&gt; to write then quit the window to make life easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the more powerful bindings, they usually come in sets of keys; what I&amp;rsquo;ve referred to as keybindings are actually called &lt;em&gt;vim motions&lt;/em&gt;. Using vim motions, you can do &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; to delete a line, or &lt;code&gt;diw&lt;/code&gt; to delete a word. These may seem illogical at first but there&amp;rsquo;s a method to the madness &amp;ndash; what a key like &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; is is an &lt;em&gt;operator&lt;/em&gt;. It waits for you to define a target, like &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; again to delete the line or &lt;code&gt;iw&lt;/code&gt; to delete &lt;em&gt;in (the) word&lt;/em&gt; that you are currently on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be totally honest, the keybinds are kinda jank, but they try their best to make at least some sort of sense. For example, where &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; is an arbitary operator, &lt;code&gt;xx&lt;/code&gt; generally operates on a line. &lt;code&gt;yy&lt;/code&gt; yanks/copies a line like how &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; deletes a line. Attempts for more sane defaults in new vim-inspired editors like Helix or Kakoune have been attempted, but regardless Vim bindings live on as the default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, what&amp;rsquo;s most important is that you stick to what you like the best and works the best for you. If you have a system set up already with whatever you&amp;rsquo;re using, it&amp;rsquo;s best to just stick with that. But if you feel limited by your current setup, and you have that itch for extra efficiency, extra flow, extra power, then you may want to consider new options like Neovim. And if you do indeed swap over, its equally as important to then stick with your current configuration once it&amp;rsquo;s good enough, instead of endlessly messing about with it; go get some work done with your fancy new tool! Only once the grievances build up past a boiling point, only then should you refactor everything all at once, it saves lotsss of trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as with learning new things, your brain can only learn so much at once, so just learn one or two new motions, and eventually you&amp;rsquo;ll know lots of powerful motions! So, go out there and have some fun~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note: I wrote this fully in Neovim btw~)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="resources"&gt;Resources
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:Tutor&lt;/code&gt; mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.lazyvim.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;LazyVim Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z4eA2eC28qg" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Video on Vim Motions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 7: Meeting With Professor Tuul Triyason</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/week-seven-project1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:02:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/week-seven-project1/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/week-seven-cover2.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 7: Meeting With Professor Tuul Triyason" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="discussion"&gt;Discussion
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had a meeting with Professor Tuul Triyason about which project or research to do that is more related to cybersecurity. He recommended me several ideas, such as building a CTF website for him with heavy topics on web security, and also a network intrusion prevention system comparative analysis. Personally, I was more intrigued by the IPS part because it is something that I have heard before from my past project member. Fortunately, he gave me the task to make a comparative analysis between Suricata and Stratosphere Lab IPS. From here, I started to do my own research on what Stratosphere Lab IPS (SLIPS) and Suricata are. This was where the professor told me to provide him a documentation on how to install and configure SLIPS together with the comparative analysis report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="ic2-website-update"&gt;IC2 Website Update
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Khush and me brainstorm some ideas on what to put in IC2 Homepage. So I came up with an idea to put in more content and images to make the homepage more engaging with parallax design.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 6: Blog adventures</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/week-six-blog1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 10:02:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/week-six-blog1/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/week-six-cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 6: Blog adventures" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="the-one-hour-wait-auntie-nid-thai-tea-"&gt;The One-Hour Wait: Auntie Nid Thai Tea 🥤
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week has been an absolute whirlwind! Andreaa and I took a deep dive into downtown Bangkok, determined to tick a major item off our bucket list: the legendary Auntie Nid Thai Tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/auntie-nid.gif"
loading="lazy"
alt="Auntie Nid performing her magic"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived to find a massive queue—we’re talking a solid one-hour wait. Thankfully, the shop knows their crowd; they had a line of chairs set up so we didn&amp;rsquo;t have to stand in the heat. But was it worth the wait?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely. The shocking part wasn&amp;rsquo;t the line; it was the price. For just 1.68 SGD, we got a drink that completely lived up to the hype. Sweet, creamy, and incredibly affordable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/auntie-nid-price.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="40 Thai Baht for all drinks. That’s a steal!"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Address: 112 Thanon Mahannop, Sao Chingcha, Phra Nakhon, Bangkok 10200&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="dessert-hunting-in-the-university-district-"&gt;Dessert Hunting in the University District 🍦
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the tea, we decided to explore the vibrant streets near Chulalongkorn University. This area is buzzing with young adults and is packed with dozens of trendy cafes and restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stumbled upon a total hidden gem called Ice Cream Somasorn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a dedicated dessert cafe that takes sundaes to the next level. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist ordering their best-sellers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Banana Crème Brûlée:&lt;/strong&gt; Perfectly caramelized and smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kopi Tiramisu:&lt;/strong&gt; A rich, coffee-infused delight that hit the spot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/icecream.gif"
loading="lazy"
alt="Somasorn Ice Cream Signature Move"
&gt; &lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/icecream2.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Banana Crème Brûlée &amp; Kopi Tiramisu"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are in the area, this is a sweet stop you can&amp;rsquo;t miss.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 6: Exploring RAG</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/week-six-project1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 10:02:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/week-six-project1/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/week-six-cover2.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 6: Exploring RAG" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="rag-testing-with-raspberry-pi-4"&gt;RAG Testing With Raspberry Pi 4
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was curious on how to implement RAG into edge devices so I borrowed the Raspberry Pi 4 provided by IC2 and work my way through at the dorm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/rp4.jpeg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Raspberry Pi 4"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="choosing-the-right-embedding-models"&gt;Choosing The Right Embedding Models
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my RAG system for Thailand climate awareness, I chose the &lt;strong&gt;sentence-transformers/multi-qa-MiniLM-L6-cos-v1&lt;/strong&gt; embedding model for document retrieval. This model is specifically designed for question-answering tasks and performs well with multi-domain queries, making it ideal for my use case where users ask various questions about Thailand&amp;rsquo;s climate data. I implemented the embedding functionality using HuggingFace Embeddings through LangChain, which allowed me to easily integrate the model with my FAISS vector store. The model efficiently converts both my document chunks and user queries into dense vector representations, enabling semantic search across my collection of PDFs, text files, and JSON documents containing Thailand climate information. I configured my system with a chunk size of 128 tokens and 20-token overlap to ensure optimal retrieval performance while maintaining context coherence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/config.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Config file"
&gt; &lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/embeddingmodels.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Installing Libraries and Dependencies"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="quick-evaluation"&gt;Quick Evaluation
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;For evaluating my RAG system&amp;rsquo;s performance, I implemented a comprehensive evaluation framework using the RAGAS library, which provides specialized metrics for retrieval-augmented generation systems. I created a custom RagEvaluator class that measures four key metrics: context recall, faithfulness, context precision, and answer relevancy. My evaluation dataset includes carefully crafted questions about Thailand&amp;rsquo;s climate data with corresponding ground truth answers, covering topics like disaster prevention responsibilities, seasonal patterns, regional climate issues, and national adaptation plans. Additionally, I built a performance benchmarking system that measures inference speed, tokens per second, memory usage, and CPU utilization during RAG operations. This dual approach allows me to assess both the quality of my system&amp;rsquo;s responses through RAGAS metrics and its operational efficiency through performance benchmarks, ensuring my Thailand climate chatbot delivers accurate information quickly and reliably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/quick-evaluation.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="RAGAS Evaluation"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 7: Makan Place nearby KMUTT</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/week-seven-blog1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 10:02:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/week-seven-blog1/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/week-seven-cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 7: Makan Place nearby KMUTT" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="eat-with-bear-a-western-feast-at-kmutts-doorstep"&gt;Eat With Bear: A Western Feast at KMUTT’s Doorstep
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The craving for a solid Western meal hit us hard today. While wandering near KMUTT, we were stopped in our tracks by a massive, unmissable bear mascot standing guard outside a storefront. Driven by hunger and curiosity, we decided to check it out.
&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/bear.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Bear"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discovered Eat With Bear, and it was exactly what we needed. The moment we stepped inside, we were greeted by a surprisingly spacious and welcoming interior—perfect for hanging out after class.
&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/bear2.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Counter"
&gt; &lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/interior.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Interior"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the real showstopper? The salad bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They offer a fantastic variety of fresh greens and toppings. And here is the best part: it’s free-flow. (Note: The unlimited salad bar is complimentary when you order specific main dishes, so check the menu first!)
&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/free.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Free Flow salad"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to go big and ordered the Chicken Burger. &amp;ldquo;Huge&amp;rdquo; is an understatement—this thing was a tower! It came paired with onion rings that were fried to golden perfection—crispy on the outside, tender on the inside, and completely addictive.
&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/burgir.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Counter"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are near the university and need a burger fix, this is the spot.
Address: 368 ซอย จุฬาฯ 1 Wang Mai, Pathum Wan, Bangkok 10330&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 5: Updates On IC2 Website</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fifth-week-project1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:02:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fifth-week-project1/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/week-five-cover-n16.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 5: Updates On IC2 Website" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="ic2-publication-page-update"&gt;IC2 Publication Page Update
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing from last week&amp;rsquo;s work, I used a collapsible content ranging from each year in descending order and pasted all the publications into the respective collapsible contents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/pubs.gif"
loading="lazy"
alt="Publication Page with all the publications"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="new-manager-in-ic2"&gt;New Manager in IC2
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professor Jonathan introduced Andreaa and me to the newly joined IC2 Research Manager, Khush Argarwal. It was immediately clear that Khush brings a wealth of experience to the table, exactly the kind of fresh perspective our current project needs! During our brief initial meeting, we discussed the strategic direction for the upcoming quarter. Khush’s background in LLM and Full Stack Development is going to be instrumental in streamlining our workflow. Andreaa and I are particularly excited about his vision for bridging the gap between our theoretical models and practical application. It feels like the start of a very productive chapter for the IC2 team.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 4: Code golfing for the advancement of AI</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fourth-week/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 13:11:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fourth-week/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fourth-week/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Week 4: Code golfing for the advancement of AI" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="introduction-to-code-golfing"&gt;Introduction to Code Golfing
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week, Professor Jonathan introduced us to &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.kaggle.com/competitions/google-code-golf-2025/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;NeurIPS 2025&lt;/a&gt;, a code golf championship intended to create a dataset to improve the performance of LLMs on novel problems. He told us to use the best existing public notebooks, and see how we could improve on any one solution. While to be honest I don&amp;rsquo;t completely see what the purpose of it would be for us, it was nonetheless interesting as I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to try my hand at Competitive Programming(-adjacent) problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="navaratri-a-traditional-hindu-festival"&gt;Navaratri, a Traditional Hindu Festival
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Khush, whom we met that day, told us about the festival as we were having dinner together alongside Esther, KM, and Fir. Sadly KM had to leave early but for the rest of us we had travelled to go see it via Grab. It was surprisingly cheap at ~25 baht per person (approx. S$1) especially considering that we had to travel all the way to the city area as the festival was held in Silom, taking around 35 minutes. To be fair&amp;hellip; it was split amongst 4 people but still&amp;hellip; unheard of in Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The festival lasts 9 nights, and we had caught it on its final day on Thursday (October 2nd). It was wayyy more packed than I had expected, and in fact more packed last year, according to Khush. It was a very lively celebration indeed, with many of the audience cheerfully chanting to one of the performers balancing a heavy pot (matka) on their heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fourth-week/dance.gif"
width="360"
height="640"
srcset="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fourth-week/dance_hu_2e23804c0e7c862f.gif 480w, https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fourth-week/dance_hu_759c25ee6dc444a2.gif 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Performer dancing with a heavy pot on his head"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="56"
data-flex-basis="135px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had to spend a lot of time walking on the curb of the other street which wasn&amp;rsquo;t blocked off for traffic (as the main street was packed to the brim and there were no proper sidewalks there), and it felt pretty dangerous as the cars were passsing by right next to us; perhaps they hadn&amp;rsquo;t anticipated such a massive turnout, there was a lot of traffic jams due to people crossing the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was really fun and by the end I got to see quite a few different gods and also got to do a offering to one of the many shrines on the side of the road. I found myself completely drenched in sweat due to the humidity from the rain the day before, yet also weirdly energised. By the time we got back, it was already 11PM and I made sure to take a good long shower in order to freshen up.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 3: Artifical Intelligence and such</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/third-week/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 13:10:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/third-week/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/third-week/cover2.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 3: Artifical Intelligence and such" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="project-update"&gt;Project Update
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Will update soon&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 4: Room Upgrade!</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/deluxe-room/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/deluxe-room/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week4-cat.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 4: Room Upgrade!" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="deluxe-room-2--type-ii"&gt;Deluxe Room 2 – Type II
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;We decided to upgrade to a larger room and asked the dorm receptionist about availability. Luckily, there was an open unit that was noticeably bigger than our current place. The price is quite reasonable as the total rent cost for one month for this room is 18000 Baht(roughly 730.23 SGD ) which is an additional 6000 Baht per month from our previous room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went for a tour and were pleasantly surprised by how much more spacious it felt — a larger living area, a roomier bedroom, and extra storage that made it easy to separate sleeping, working, and relaxing zones. It immediately felt like a meaningful upgrade in comfort and functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week4-room.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Room view"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="living-room"&gt;Living Room
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The living room includes a compact kitchenette with a small kitchen table and a dining table placed right beside the study area. That setup makes it easy to work or eat in the living room while keeping the bedroom as a separate, private space. The dining table also doubles as an extra workspace when needed, giving us more surface area and flexibility without crowding the study. The toilet and study table was pretty much the same as last time. Well at least we can work from home!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week4-room2.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Living Room View 2"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bedroom"&gt;Bedroom
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though the bedroom layout gives a familiar “hey, remember this?” vibe from our old place, the upgrade is obvious — we finally have our own closet! Andrea’s side comes with a cheerful stack of shelves that’s already hosting plants, notebooks, snack reserves, and a suspiciously large sock collection. The closet eats my luggage like a polite little black hole and has extra shelves for shoes, boxes, and all those chargers that used to roam free. A string of fairy lights and a cozy rug turned the corner into a tiny chill nook — same cozy bedroom energy, but with actual storage and instant bragging rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week4-room3.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Bedroom view"
&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week4-bedroom.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Bedroom view 2"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And since we have our own closet, this time its much more bigger. I can even fit my luggage inside! Additionally, there are several shelves inside the closet to put bunch of your stuff there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week4-closet.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Closet view"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="balcony"&gt;Balcony
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the most interesting part is our balcony — we’ve got an unobstructed view of the city that completely changes how the place feels. It’s big enough for a small bistro set, so mornings are now for coffee and people-watching, and evenings are for winding down with the skyline. The railing gives a clear sightline without feeling exposed, and a soft string of lights makes it a cosy spot after dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week4-balcony.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Balcony view"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 2: in Bangkok for our KMUTT Internship</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/second-week/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 10:02:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/second-week/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/second-week/cover2.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 2: in Bangkok for our KMUTT Internship" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="exploring-projects"&gt;Exploring Projects
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andreaa and I had an opportunity to explore different kinds of projects. One of it is to collaborate with the full-time students and work on their capstone projects. KM, one of the full-time student suggest to us that Andreaa and I can cotribute to his one of his projects which is Audio-Language Models which involves a mixture of AI and cybersecurity. To elaborate further, KM&amp;rsquo;s project is mainly focus on the frequency of the Audio Language Models that converts from audio to text. He used that to determine if the prompts are able to bypass the model&amp;rsquo;s safeguard and produce harmful responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="project-updates"&gt;Project Updates
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After getting familiar with the Ghost website builder, Andreaa and I fixed the responsiveness of the IC2 Website. We also seeked guidance from KM for the publication sources that was web-scraped using python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/second-week/responsiveness_b4.jpg"
width="1300"
height="688"
srcset="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/second-week/responsiveness_b4_hu_11ea1855e7da5267.jpg 480w, https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/second-week/responsiveness_b4_hu_a163f44e52c0965f.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Responsiveness before we fix"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="188"
data-flex-basis="453px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/second-week/responsiveness_after.jpg"
width="1271"
height="697"
srcset="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/second-week/responsiveness_after_hu_764e2d12106f3734.jpg 480w, https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/second-week/responsiveness_after_hu_4d9f9e9d3d4dbf.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Responsiveness after we fix"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="182"
data-flex-basis="437px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First week in Bangkok for our KMUTT Internship</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/first-week/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/first-week/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/first-week/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post First week in Bangkok for our KMUTT Internship" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For my 3-month internship, I decided to choose one that was abroad as I wanted to learn from people with experiences that I&amp;rsquo;d never find in Singapore. Little did I know, during my first week of internship abroad in interning at King Mongkut’s University of Technology Thonburi (KMUTT) in Thailand, I&amp;rsquo;d be utterly blown away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="our-time-in-bkk"&gt;Our time in BKK
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;After being introduced around, I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten a bit more familiarised with the school&amp;rsquo;s environment and the local culture. I&amp;rsquo;ve explored the surrounding area with my roommate and new friend Firdaus, who has been very proactive in finding new places for us. he has also been a good teammate, being very receptive to my advice and my ideas for working together on projects, and has collaborated greatly so far on brainstorming for new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve met a few people who&amp;rsquo;ve helped me greatly in getting integrated into the environment, like my supervisor Dr. Jonathan H. Chan, Professor Chonlameth, and IC2 student KM. Their knowledge has been beneficial to me; for example Dr. Chonlameth helped introduce me to some student projects, while Dr. Jonathan helped give me a run down on what I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="learning-about-projects"&gt;Learning about Projects
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the students, Firdaus and I learnt about AI-related projects (which we may be assigned to), such as a makeup recommender that recommends foundation based on skin colour, and contour based on face shape &amp;ndash; which used YOLOv12 to classify face shapes. It also used facial segmentation image models to apply a filter (e.g. foundation, blush) in order to preview the makeup. Another project was that of an AI FAQ chatbot for the school which used RAG. in both, we learnt a bit about the tech stack used for the projects, like how certain services were containerised, and how they were used; this gave me a bit of insight into different architectures and how to set them up depending on the scope of our project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/first-week/IMG_7090.jpg"
width="4032"
height="3024"
srcset="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/first-week/IMG_7090_hu_50919a7740ac20ff.jpg 480w, https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/first-week/IMG_7090_hu_bd89e3ce95dfe46f.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Notes on the AI-powered makeup recommendation project"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KM covered a few of his projects (and those of other students): a time-series regression model to create synthetic data for market conditions (e.g. bull/bear conditions), a past climate change robot &amp;ndash; that used LLMs to spread awareness, and his current research project which is about developing a unified audio purification model/framework for (Large) Audio Language Models [(L)ALMs] to defend from attacks meant to cause a large language model (LLM) to operate in an unintended way (e.g. by bypassing guardrails). The LALM project was still in the research phase, covering research within the past few years on the topic, and how they weren&amp;rsquo;t unified &amp;ndash; the current purification models were &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; meant to defend against attacks for one particular type of model, like a classification or speech-to-text model. They were very interesting as KM is a very technical person by nature, and the slides he presents were very detailed, covering the exact methodology and machine learning techniques used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KM has a deep interest in AI topics and has read up on many papers, so his deep experience with the topic makes me feel like an apprentice to a master in his craft &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m able to learn a lot more about the nitty gritty details of topics that I was only previously acquainted with from him. His deep understanding of the technology involved really shines through, being able to effortlessly explain complex topics in a simple and concise manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, his deep understanding of the technology involved &amp;ndash; gained through his interest and research into papers regarding artificial intelligence, really shines through when giving presentations; he is able to effortlessly explain complex topics in a concise and understandable manner, making him a joy to learn from and to ask questions to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="our-work"&gt;Our work
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were told by Dr. Jonathan to brainstorm some possible ideas and solutions for our projects, and we were assigned a few things that we could work on &amp;ndash; for example, updating the website for the IC2 Research Center, or refining a robot that IC2 has been worked on for a previous hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I have just started brainstorming and taking notes on the projects, and any new knowledge that comes my way. In the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;ve set up this very blog and added some features that we would need (like the Author section, which wasn&amp;rsquo;t in the template).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also learnt a few new things about AI, like how LALMs don&amp;rsquo;t actually have intermediate steps in converting audio input to text output (as opposed to first captioning the audio and passing it into the model), and even a bit about how to read candlestick graphs &amp;ndash; which is useful in understanding stock graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="exploring-the-area"&gt;Exploring the area
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/first-week/IMG_7093.jpg"
width="8293"
height="3744"
srcset="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/first-week/IMG_7093_hu_ab4b7c4b90ed66e4.jpg 480w, https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/first-week/IMG_7093_hu_4c77b92bef373cc4.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Panorama from the IC2 Research Lab"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="221"
data-flex-basis="531px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike Singapore which has been forced into verticality due to its limited land area, Bangkok is held up to no such restriction. The high-rises and skyscrapers quickly disappear from my periphery as I take the bus away from the city, and it&amp;rsquo;s instead replaced with shorter, less fanciful yet just-as-practical buildings &amp;ndash; looking similar to many Southeast Asian countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides that, me and Firdaus explored our surroundings; going to malls in the city area and finding tasty spots around the KMUTT. The path to the mall was intertwined with their rail system with a dizzying amount of verticality, with shops integrating into the rail exits integrating into mall entrances, creating an almost cyberpunk-like feel. There was also much more life and variety in the malls; shops owned by both large chains and small businesses co-existed &amp;ndash; a stark contrast with Singapore&amp;rsquo;s, where rent in large malls (often owned by Capitaland) are too unsustainable for small businesses, pushing them to smaller, less fancy malls at the fringe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to mention, food here has been both delicious and cheap, with the meals of some days only totalling up to 140 baht (~ S$5.60) &amp;ndash; and that&amp;rsquo;s with both drinks and dessert!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/first-week/IMG_7068.jpg"
width="4032"
height="3024"
srcset="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/first-week/IMG_7068_hu_bfffc53dfbba8689.jpg 480w, https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/first-week/IMG_7068_hu_18fb3bc0b0488119.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Duck noodles with duck eggs (nom)"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="message-of-the-week-ie-conclusion"&gt;Message of the Week (i.e. Conclusion)
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m grateful that I took this opportunity to leave my comfort zone and to have an internship overseas, seeing as how I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to learn so much and experience things that I would never have the chance to in Singapore. The enthusiasm of the people around me in their course of study and fueled my desire to strive to better myself in AI, and I hope to continue learning and working with my new-found friends.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 1: Heliconia House</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/superior-room/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/superior-room/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/week1-kmutt.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 1: Heliconia House" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="superior-room--type-i"&gt;Superior Room – Type I
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;At first the room looked like it might be cramped, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually pretty cozy. The layout is straightforward: a bed, a simple desk, and a little balcony that brings in good light and doubles as a quiet spot. We used the balcony for a small clothes rack — great for drying stuff without taking over the room. The rental cost for this room is 12000 Baht(roughly 486.82 SGD)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall vibe: simple and functional. There&amp;rsquo;s enough storage for the basics and a comfy setup for studying and sleeping — perfect for settling into the semester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week1-bed.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Room view"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week1-closet.gif"
loading="lazy"
alt="Balcony area"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="closet"&gt;Closet
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The closet&amp;rsquo;s on the smaller side, so we ended up sharing and organizing by how often we use things. Stuff that helped:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slim hangers make a big difference for maximizing rod space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small basket for daily accessories keeps the surface clutter-free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roll or fold casual clothes to save space on the shelves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week1-closet.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Closet Before"
&gt; &lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week1-closet-after.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Closet After"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Little tweaks like these make the whole place feel more organized and relaxed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="study-area"&gt;Study Area
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study table was very spacious and became my go‑to spot for working from home. It easily held my laptop, an external monitor, and a few reference books without feeling crowded, so long stretches of focused work were comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What helped make it a proper WFH setup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lighting: natural light from the balcony plus a small adjustable desk lamp for late nights kept eye fatigue down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power &amp;amp; connectivity: a compact power strip and a short cable organizer meant chargers and peripherals were within reach; the campus Wi‑Fi was reliable for video calls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organization: a slim drawer caddy and a pen cup kept small items tidy; a dock or USB hub minimized desk clutter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comfort &amp;amp; focus: noise‑canceling headphones and a simple routine (clear desk at the end of the day, set hours) made it easier to switch into “work mode.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small additions like a mouse pad with wrist support, a plant, or a dedicated notebook made the workspace feel personal and productive — a surprisingly good setup for studying and remote work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week1-room-study.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Study Room"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="toilet"&gt;Toilet
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bathroom&amp;rsquo;s fine — nothing fancy. The toilet bowl felt a bit small for me personally, but there’s a water heater, so hot showers are covered. Overall, it does the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week1-toilet.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Toilet View"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>