<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Week4 on Placeholder &amp; Co.</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/tags/week4/</link><description>Recent content in Week4 on Placeholder &amp; Co.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:02:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/tags/week4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Week 4: Code golfing for the advancement of AI</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fourth-week/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 13:11:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fourth-week/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fourth-week/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Week 4: Code golfing for the advancement of AI" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="introduction-to-code-golfing"&gt;Introduction to Code Golfing
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week, Professor Jonathan introduced us to &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.kaggle.com/competitions/google-code-golf-2025/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;NeurIPS 2025&lt;/a&gt;, a code golf championship intended to create a dataset to improve the performance of LLMs on novel problems. He told us to use the best existing public notebooks, and see how we could improve on any one solution. While to be honest I don&amp;rsquo;t completely see what the purpose of it would be for us, it was nonetheless interesting as I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to try my hand at Competitive Programming(-adjacent) problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="navaratri-a-traditional-hindu-festival"&gt;Navaratri, a Traditional Hindu Festival
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Khush, whom we met that day, told us about the festival as we were having dinner together alongside Esther, KM, and Fir. Sadly KM had to leave early but for the rest of us we had travelled to go see it via Grab. It was surprisingly cheap at ~25 baht per person (approx. S$1) especially considering that we had to travel all the way to the city area as the festival was held in Silom, taking around 35 minutes. To be fair&amp;hellip; it was split amongst 4 people but still&amp;hellip; unheard of in Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The festival lasts 9 nights, and we had caught it on its final day on Thursday (October 2nd). It was wayyy more packed than I had expected, and in fact more packed last year, according to Khush. It was a very lively celebration indeed, with many of the audience cheerfully chanting to one of the performers balancing a heavy pot (matka) on their heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fourth-week/dance.gif"
width="360"
height="640"
srcset="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fourth-week/dance_hu_2e23804c0e7c862f.gif 480w, https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fourth-week/dance_hu_759c25ee6dc444a2.gif 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Performer dancing with a heavy pot on his head"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="56"
data-flex-basis="135px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had to spend a lot of time walking on the curb of the other street which wasn&amp;rsquo;t blocked off for traffic (as the main street was packed to the brim and there were no proper sidewalks there), and it felt pretty dangerous as the cars were passsing by right next to us; perhaps they hadn&amp;rsquo;t anticipated such a massive turnout, there was a lot of traffic jams due to people crossing the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was really fun and by the end I got to see quite a few different gods and also got to do a offering to one of the many shrines on the side of the road. I found myself completely drenched in sweat due to the humidity from the rain the day before, yet also weirdly energised. By the time we got back, it was already 11PM and I made sure to take a good long shower in order to freshen up.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 4: Room Upgrade!</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/deluxe-room/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/deluxe-room/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week4-cat.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 4: Room Upgrade!" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="deluxe-room-2--type-ii"&gt;Deluxe Room 2 – Type II
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;We decided to upgrade to a larger room and asked the dorm receptionist about availability. Luckily, there was an open unit that was noticeably bigger than our current place. The price is quite reasonable as the total rent cost for one month for this room is 18000 Baht(roughly 730.23 SGD ) which is an additional 6000 Baht per month from our previous room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went for a tour and were pleasantly surprised by how much more spacious it felt — a larger living area, a roomier bedroom, and extra storage that made it easy to separate sleeping, working, and relaxing zones. It immediately felt like a meaningful upgrade in comfort and functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week4-room.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Room view"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="living-room"&gt;Living Room
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The living room includes a compact kitchenette with a small kitchen table and a dining table placed right beside the study area. That setup makes it easy to work or eat in the living room while keeping the bedroom as a separate, private space. The dining table also doubles as an extra workspace when needed, giving us more surface area and flexibility without crowding the study. The toilet and study table was pretty much the same as last time. Well at least we can work from home!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week4-room2.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Living Room View 2"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bedroom"&gt;Bedroom
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though the bedroom layout gives a familiar “hey, remember this?” vibe from our old place, the upgrade is obvious — we finally have our own closet! Andrea’s side comes with a cheerful stack of shelves that’s already hosting plants, notebooks, snack reserves, and a suspiciously large sock collection. The closet eats my luggage like a polite little black hole and has extra shelves for shoes, boxes, and all those chargers that used to roam free. A string of fairy lights and a cozy rug turned the corner into a tiny chill nook — same cozy bedroom energy, but with actual storage and instant bragging rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week4-room3.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Bedroom view"
&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week4-bedroom.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Bedroom view 2"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And since we have our own closet, this time its much more bigger. I can even fit my luggage inside! Additionally, there are several shelves inside the closet to put bunch of your stuff there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week4-closet.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Closet view"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="balcony"&gt;Balcony
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the most interesting part is our balcony — we’ve got an unobstructed view of the city that completely changes how the place feels. It’s big enough for a small bistro set, so mornings are now for coffee and people-watching, and evenings are for winding down with the skyline. The railing gives a clear sightline without feeling exposed, and a soft string of lights makes it a cosy spot after dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/week4-balcony.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Balcony view"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>