<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Placeholder &amp; Co.</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/categories/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Placeholder &amp; Co.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:02:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Week 7: Meeting With Professor Tuul Triyason</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/week-seven-project1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:02:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/week-seven-project1/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/week-seven-cover2.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 7: Meeting With Professor Tuul Triyason" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="discussion"&gt;Discussion
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had a meeting with Professor Tuul Triyason about which project or research to do that is more related to cybersecurity. He recommended me several ideas, such as building a CTF website for him with heavy topics on web security, and also a network intrusion prevention system comparative analysis. Personally, I was more intrigued by the IPS part because it is something that I have heard before from my past project member. Fortunately, he gave me the task to make a comparative analysis between Suricata and Stratosphere Lab IPS. From here, I started to do my own research on what Stratosphere Lab IPS (SLIPS) and Suricata are. This was where the professor told me to provide him a documentation on how to install and configure SLIPS together with the comparative analysis report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="ic2-website-update"&gt;IC2 Website Update
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Khush and me brainstorm some ideas on what to put in IC2 Homepage. So I came up with an idea to put in more content and images to make the homepage more engaging with parallax design.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 6: Exploring RAG</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/week-six-project1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 10:02:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/week-six-project1/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/week-six-cover2.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 6: Exploring RAG" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="rag-testing-with-raspberry-pi-4"&gt;RAG Testing With Raspberry Pi 4
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was curious on how to implement RAG into edge devices so I borrowed the Raspberry Pi 4 provided by IC2 and work my way through at the dorm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/rp4.jpeg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Raspberry Pi 4"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="choosing-the-right-embedding-models"&gt;Choosing The Right Embedding Models
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my RAG system for Thailand climate awareness, I chose the &lt;strong&gt;sentence-transformers/multi-qa-MiniLM-L6-cos-v1&lt;/strong&gt; embedding model for document retrieval. This model is specifically designed for question-answering tasks and performs well with multi-domain queries, making it ideal for my use case where users ask various questions about Thailand&amp;rsquo;s climate data. I implemented the embedding functionality using HuggingFace Embeddings through LangChain, which allowed me to easily integrate the model with my FAISS vector store. The model efficiently converts both my document chunks and user queries into dense vector representations, enabling semantic search across my collection of PDFs, text files, and JSON documents containing Thailand climate information. I configured my system with a chunk size of 128 tokens and 20-token overlap to ensure optimal retrieval performance while maintaining context coherence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/config.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Config file"
&gt; &lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/embeddingmodels.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Installing Libraries and Dependencies"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="quick-evaluation"&gt;Quick Evaluation
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;For evaluating my RAG system&amp;rsquo;s performance, I implemented a comprehensive evaluation framework using the RAGAS library, which provides specialized metrics for retrieval-augmented generation systems. I created a custom RagEvaluator class that measures four key metrics: context recall, faithfulness, context precision, and answer relevancy. My evaluation dataset includes carefully crafted questions about Thailand&amp;rsquo;s climate data with corresponding ground truth answers, covering topics like disaster prevention responsibilities, seasonal patterns, regional climate issues, and national adaptation plans. Additionally, I built a performance benchmarking system that measures inference speed, tokens per second, memory usage, and CPU utilization during RAG operations. This dual approach allows me to assess both the quality of my system&amp;rsquo;s responses through RAGAS metrics and its operational efficiency through performance benchmarks, ensuring my Thailand climate chatbot delivers accurate information quickly and reliably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/quick-evaluation.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="RAGAS Evaluation"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Week 5: Updates On IC2 Website</title><link>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fifth-week-project1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:02:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/p/fifth-week-project1/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/week-five-cover-n16.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week 5: Updates On IC2 Website" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="ic2-publication-page-update"&gt;IC2 Publication Page Update
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing from last week&amp;rsquo;s work, I used a collapsible content ranging from each year in descending order and pasted all the publications into the respective collapsible contents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://sensura-san.github.io/silly-blog/img/pubs.gif"
loading="lazy"
alt="Publication Page with all the publications"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="new-manager-in-ic2"&gt;New Manager in IC2
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professor Jonathan introduced Andreaa and me to the newly joined IC2 Research Manager, Khush Argarwal. It was immediately clear that Khush brings a wealth of experience to the table, exactly the kind of fresh perspective our current project needs! During our brief initial meeting, we discussed the strategic direction for the upcoming quarter. Khush’s background in LLM and Full Stack Development is going to be instrumental in streamlining our workflow. Andreaa and I are particularly excited about his vision for bridging the gap between our theoretical models and practical application. It feels like the start of a very productive chapter for the IC2 team.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>